( Thunder crashes)
(swing music playing)
( Rain falling )
( Music ceases )
BILLY: Whoa!
STEPHANIE:
All the food's gonna go bad.
Yeah, I drew up a list.
I'll hit the store
before it gets all bought out.
Fuck.
- Can you save it?
- No. No way.
No, I gotta start over from scratch.
I'll call the studio
when the phones get back up,
see if they can extend my deadline.
STEPHANIE:
What choice do they have?
( David sighs heavily )
You kiddin'?
They could whip up some bad
Photoshop poster in an afternoon.
They do it all the time.
Two big heads.
I should have brought it downstairs
with me last night.
Just stupid, I guess.
Well, sweetie,
you couldn't exactly know
that a tree was gonna come flying
through the window.
Yeah, I'll hit the hardware store too,
get some plastic sheeting
and duct tape
and seal this up
before it gets dark, you know.
Order in some new glass.
Oh, you know what?
That was your--
That was your grandfather's tree,
the one he planted.
- Ohh.
- Used to play in that tree.
It's just stuff, though.
You know, we're safe.
That's all that counts.
Yeah.
Mom, Dad, you gotta come see!
Hey, Billy, take it easy, all right?
I really don't want you running
all over the place.
But you gotta come look.
The boathouse is all bashed!
Holy crap!
Billy.
Sorry, Mom, but you just
gotta come! Come on!
Whoa!
Whoa.
- Whoa.
- Come on.
Having spoken,
the Doomsayer departs.
- BILLY: Come on!
- ( Stephanie chuckles )
How do you two always manage
to make me laugh?
- You have incredibly low standards.
- Mm-hmm.
Let's go, uh, see the damage.
No.
- Norton's tree.
- ( sighs ) Yeah.
You mean the dead one
I've been asking him
to take down for three years
before it finally blew over?
That tree?
- Really got smooshed.
- You ain't kiddin'.
Look at that.
What is it, Daddy?
Mist.
- On the lake?
- We've had mist on the lake before.
Coming off the mountain like that?
Two fronts meeting,
left over from the storm,
something like that.
You sure?
Honey, I'm not the weatherman.
Why don't you take Billy,
get him dressed.
I'll take him to town with me.
Okay. Where you going?
I'm gonna go have a little chat
with our neighbor about his tree.
Hon.
Don't worry, I'm not gonna
punch him in the nose.
You know what he's gonna say.
He's gonna say, "Sue me,"
which, I don't know, maybe we should.
Honey, one property dispute
with this guy is enough to last me a lifetime.
I'm gonna ask
for his insurance information.
- Okay.
- That's all.
Yeah.
( Norton grunting,
pulling chainsaw chain )
NORTON: Ohh!
Mother fucker!
Aw, shit!
Ohh, you mother fucker!
Cock sucker!
"Turn on.
"Full choke.
Pull five... choke."
I guess you've seen the--
Boathouse.
Yeah, and--?
Nothin'.
Just think we should trade
insurance info, you know?
That's all.
( Scoffs )
Oh, my insurance guy's
gonna love me.
Oh.
Shit. The 1980.
NORTON: I was gonna bring
the station wagon, but...
I don't know, the weather was so beautiful
coming out of New York, I just-- you know, top down.
I'm sorry, man. I mean it.
Sincerely.
- That's nice of you to say.
- No, that car was cherry.
I hate to see it like that.
Okay, I'll tell you what,
I'll find my insurance guy's number,
I'll bring it by later.
- That okay?
- No problem.
So, uh, David--
You're not heading into town today
by any chance, are you?
DAVID:
Well, CMP's out in force.
Maybe we'll get our power back.
NORTON:
I know. Some storm, huh?
One for the books, yeah.
For a moment there last night,
I thought we were gonna take off
and head for Oz.
WZON is off the air,
but Portland's still broadcasting.
- Daddy, look.
- Ah.
Guys from the base.
- From up the mountain?
- Uh-huh.
The Arrowhead Project?
Well, you're a local.
Any idea what they do up there?
Missile defense research...
You know, I'm sure
you've heard the stories.
Oh, sure.
The woman at the Laundromat
says that, uh,
they have a crashed flying saucer
up there with frozen alien bodies.
Right. Miss Edna. Yeah.
Miss Tabloid.
( chuckles )
"I Had Bigfoot's Baby."
"Satan's Face Appears
in Oil Well Fire."
You know, real reliable stuff.
DAVID:Well, they're in a hurry.
Maybe their power's out too.
Huh. Still no signal.
Why don't you go ahead?
I'm gonna try Steph on a pay phone.
Can I go with Mr. Norton, Daddy?
Sure, if you promise
to hold his hand, I guess.
- BILLY: Yeah.
- Yeah.
Here's a list.
- Sure.
- Okay?
Meet you guys in there.
Hold hands.
MAN: I'm sorry.
I didn't know it was your sister.
( Pulsing tone )
( Clicks phone cradle;
pulsing tone continues )
BOY:Those look so freaky!
Hmm.
( Chatter )
- Sally, hey.
- Hey, Mr. Drayton.
You guys look jammed up.
Yeah, well, half the staff
didn't show, plus the power's out.
Oh, no. What, no backup generator?
Only to keep the food cold.
Everything else, welcome to the Dark Ages,
and bring your checkbook.
Hey, Thursday night,
Steph and I want a date night.
- Baby-sit?
- Heck, yeah. I'm there.
Oh, my God.
OLLIE: ( humorless chuckle )
The storm.
Everybody's stockin' up.
Been like this since we opened.
Crappy day, huh?
Eh, everyone's a little
pissed off this morning.
'Morning, Mrs. Carmody.
With lines like these,
I don't know how good it is,
but I guess we'll have to make do.
- Keep your head down, pal.
- I know it.
Hey, champ.
Your wife should be a doctor.
She could make a fortune
in Manhattan with this handwriting.
Yeah, it takes some getting used to.
Why don't you get your stuff?
I'll meet you at the checkout.
Okay, done.
Hey, David,
thanks for helping me out today.
Are you and Mr. Norton
gonna be friends now, Daddy?
Oh, I don't know.
"Friends" might be stretching it a little.
I guess you're not mad
at each other anymore.
I guess not.
Hey. And that's a start, huh?
BUD: I'm sorry, ma'am,
the registers are down.
The power outage got us too.
Hopefully we'll have
power up pretty soon.
( Indistinct conversation )
( Chuckles )
- The bus leaves in 30 minutes.
- We'll make it, okay?
You guys get the goodies.
I'll wait in line.
BUD: Yes, ma'am, those are $1.25.
I need some change on register five.
Good morning, Ms. Reppler.
BILLY: Hello, Ms. Reppler.
Well, hello to you, Billy Drayton.
How'd you hold up in the storm?
We had a tree come through the picture window
last night, right in my studio.
And the boathouse got all smooshed.
Mr. Norton's tree fell on it.
- IRENE: Ouch.
- Yeah.
IRENE:Sorry to hear that.
DAVID: How'd you guys make out?
HATTIE: Oh, we're fine.
It's the listings I'm worried about.
At the very least, I'll bet every one
of our "For Sale" signs fell over.
IRENE: We had damage
at the school, wouldn't you know?
That's what we get for not fixing
that roof when we should've,
but with funds being cut every year...
You'd think educating children
would be more of a priority in this country,
but you'd be wrong.
Government's got better things
to spend our money on,
like corporate handouts
and building bombs.
( Passing sirens wail )
( Fire truck horn blares )
Daddy, is there a fire?
Is Mommy all right?
I'm sure she's fine.
Don't worry, okay?
Mind what you're doing, Sally.
SOLDIER: Oh, come on,
we got 10 days' leave.
Check our papers.
Look, I told you,
all leaves are cancelled.
I don't know why.
I gotta go check the pharmacy out.
Three men meet me
back at the Jeep in five minutes.
That's an order.
Shit, man! Another half an hour,
and we'd have been gone.
( Klaxon blares )
( Klaxon continues )
Oh, my God!
Something in the mist!
- ( Excited shouting )
- Something in the mist took John Lee!
Dan, catch your breath.
Something in the mist took John Lee.
I could hear him screaming.
Shut the doors! Shut the doors!
My God!
Daddy, I'm scared.
Can we go home?
( Klaxon blares )
DAN: Don't go out there.
There's something in the mist.
It took John Lee.
MAN: Screw that!
I'm gettin' in my car.
Mister, no!
( Police siren wails )
( Police siren ceases )
( Keys jangling )
( Man screaming )
Oh, shit.
Please hold me.
- ( Billy whimpers )
- It's okay, it's okay.
CORNELL: It's a pollution cloud.
The mills down in Rumford.
Some kind of chemical explosion.
Has to be.
MAN: ( whispering )
What is it?
What's going on?
It's death.
Aah!
( Crashing and rumbling )
( Screaming and shouting )
( Screaming )
( Building girders groaning )
- ( Screaming and shouting )
- MAN: Stay down!
BILLY: Daddy!
( Rumbling stops )
( Woman coughing )
( Woman weeping )
MAN: ( faintly )
You all right? You okay?
( Coughing )
That was an earthquake.
I tell you, the goddamn mills blew up!
OLLIE: Is everyone okay?
Is anyone hurt?
Everybody just stay put, okay?
Just stay inside the store.
I can't. I can't stay here.
I gotta get home to my kids.
MRS. CARMODY: No.
No, don't go out there.
It's death out there.
It's the end of days.
Stop it, okay? Stop it.
NORTON: Please, everybody,
everybody just relax, okay?
He's right. Let's just stay cool.
Let's just try to figure out
what happened.
I'm sorry, I-- I can't just stay here.
I have to get home to my kids.
Ma'am, no, you can't go out there.
Could be a poisonous gas cloud.
Didn't you hear that man screaming?
I agree. Let's stay here
until we figure it out.
WOMAN: You're not listening!
I can't stay here.
Wanda's looking after little Victor.
She's only eight.
Sometimes she forgets
she's supposed to be watching him.
I told them I'd only be gone
a few minutes.
She's only eight.
For their sakes, don't.
Well, isn't anybody gonna help me?
DAVID: ( softly ) Shh. It's okay, pal.
Won't somebody here see a lady home?
You?
- DAVID: ( softly ) It's okay, buddy.
- You?
Ma'am, please,
I got my own boy to worry about.
I hope you all rot in hell.
OLLIE: Ma'am, please, wait until--
( Soft weeping )
BUD: Okay,
let's start cleaning up, okay?
Get the spilled bottles,
broken glass, stuff like that.
Aisle three has medical supplies.
- ( Billy crying )
- It's okay. It's okay.
All right, easy, champ.
Come on.
All right, hey, hey, hey.
Can't keep crying like this, pal.
Come on!
Come on, you're gonna hurt yourself.
- Come on, are you all right?
- I want Mommy!
All right, I know you want Mommy.
( Very softly )
All right, just try to breathe.
Just try to breathe, okay?
( Billy crying )
Just try to breathe, pal.
That's okay.
- ( Billy crying )
- It's all right.
I haven't seen him suck his thumb
like this since he was two years old.
AMANDA: He's in shock.
I think we all are.
IRENE: You haven't met.
Amanda Dunfrey.
She's new in town
as of this semester.
Teaches third grade
and the special ed kids,
now that Mosher's retired.
She's wonderful.
The kids love her.
And David's an artist.
He does movie posters and such.
And me...
Lord, I'm babbling away
like some old biddy at a tea party!
My nerves are jangled, I guess.
Boy settle down?
How is he?
Still hot.
Why don't I get him some aspirin.
- Aisle three.
- Okay.
Thanks.
DAVID: How's Dan?
His nose stopped bleedin'.
He's calmer now.
Somebody gave him a Valium.
Can't believe the way he ran in here.
Never seen him like that.
I need something to cover my boy up.
Got any blankets?
Furniture pads. Loadin' dock.
Gonna keep checkin' on people.
If you need anything, just holler.
You bet. Sally, you mind?
Oh, I'd love to. I really should
help him clean up.
- I'll take him.
- Okay.
Daddy, don't go.
No, I'll be gone two seconds, Big Bill.
Come on, I'm gonna get your blanket.
Mrs. Reppler's here,
and so is Mrs. Turman.
I'll be close by, okay?
- Okay.
- Don't worry, I'm not far. Okay?
Let me look at you.
Hmm?
HATTIE: Wanna lie down?
Yeah.
There you go.
NORTON: Soon as it blows away,
we can walk out of here safe and free,
but we have to be smart about it.
First thing we need to do
is keep our wits about us
and find out what's happened.
MAN: Well, how we gonna
do that, my man?
We've got no phone signal,
got no radio.
NORTON:I'm sure they're working
on those problems as we speak.
It stands to reason
that restoring communications
would be their top priority.
( Machinery hums )
( David coughs )
( Coughing )
Jeez!
( Coughs )
Oh, shit.
- ( Sharp crack )
- Ow!
Shit!
( Grunts )
God damn it!
Ow! Ow!
Bitch!
NORTON: It's obvious that we're--
We're in some kind
of natural disaster here.
MAN: Ain't nothin' obvious
about this sombitch from where I sit.
CORNELL: There ain't nothin'
natural about it either.
MAN: That's right.
MRS. CARMODY: It's Judgment Day,
and it's come round at last.
There is nothing more obvious
or natural than that.
MAN: Ohh, fuck, now.
MRS. CARMODY: You've done that to yourself
by a life of sin and dissolution.
( Metal rumbling and creaking )
( Rumbling and creaking cease )
( Creaking loudly )
Hey, whoa! David!
DAVID: Hey, you guys hear that?
The generator?
We're just gonna check it out.
No, no, I turned the generator off.
It-- it was backing up.
- N-nobody else heard that sound?
- What sound?
I don't know, like a... weird noise,
back there in the dark.
Like something was, like,
pressing against the door.
Did you hear it
before the lights went out, or after?
No, only after.
After, but, look, I heard it, okay?
- Nobody's calling you a liar.
- That's what it sounds like.
JIM: No, no, no, no.
Now, don't be thattaway, Mr. Drayton.
You had a scare, no doubt.
What say we all go check it out? Here.
JIM: Oooopf!
( chuckles )
Man.
It's pretty rank in here.
- Myron, go check it out.
- All right.
Go on, fire it up.
( Generator whirrs to life )
JIM: ( laughing )
All right!
Shut it off!
Holy crow, don't that stink!
MYRON: Something's got
the exhaust vent plugged up from the outside.
You get it running long enough
to raise that door a little,
I'll go out and clear
whatever's blockin' it.
No, no, you can't do that.
MYRON: Why not?
It's an electric door, right?
Well, yeah, but it may not be wise
to send him out there.
MYRON: Okay, I'll do it.
No, look, it's not about
who goes out there.
What, don't you think I can do it?
Hey! I want to go!
It was my idea.
Well, wait, just stop, okay?
- J - Jim, right?
- JIM: Mm-hmm.
Myron? You guys are--
You, well, you don't seem
to understand,
or you're tr yin' real hard not to.
This is no ordinary mist, okay?
You open that door,
and something gets in here.
NORM: Like what?
Well, like whatever
made that noise I heard.
Are you guys being willfully dense?
Mr. Drayton, you'll pardon me,
but I'm not convinced
that you heard anything.
I mean, we're not hearing
anything now, right? Anybody?
See? ( chuckles )
Now, I know, I know--
you're a big shot artist
with connections in New York
and Hollywood and all like that,
but that don't make you better
than anybody else, not in my book.
Hey, I didn't say that.
Nor do I like being
talked down to or called stupid
by a guy who went to college,
just 'cause he's got the jitters.
Fellas, it doesn't even matter
about the generator.
The food'll keep without it.
Kid, I'm gonna start the motor, you raise the door,
and you yell out when you got enough room.
Yeah. Okay, good.
DAVID: Wait.
This is-- you guys gonna let
this kid risk his life
over a generator
that doesn't even matter?
Would you just
shut the fuck up already?
OLLIE: Norm!
JIM:Listen, Mr. Drayton,
I tell you what.
The next time you got somethin' to say,
you count your teeth,
because I'm sick to death
of your bullshit.
All right? Come on, Myron.
- DAVID: This is crazy!
- OLLIE: Leave 'em be.
What am I, impugning
their manhood or something?
Listen, they've lost
their sense of proportion.
What's going on here?
Out there in the market,
they were scared and confused.
In here, there's a problem
they can solve,
so they're goddamn gonna solve it.
- MYRON: Ready, kid?
- Let's rock.
Norm, come on.
Don't, man.
( Generator whirrs to life )
DAVID: It's a mistake.
Pussy.
Go up!
So...
any boogeymen?
( Jim laughs )
JIM:Pretty scary, ain't it, Norm?
Yeah, right.
( laughter )
MYRON: Norm.
Norm!
What the fuck!
Ahh! Get it off! Get it off!
Get this friggin' thing off me!
Get it off! Help me!
Help me! Help me!
Aah! Aaahhh!
Jesus!
( Norm shouting )
There's more! There's more!
Somebody help me.
What the fuck are you waitin' for?
( Norm crying and shouting )
Aaahhhh!
Hang on!
Hold him still!
Aaahhhh!
Oh, Jesus!
( Norm grunting and straining )
( Monster sniffing )
MYRON: Aah!
Aah!
JIM: Shit! Oh, shit!
Oh, shit!
OLLIE: David, it's no good!
Aah!
DAVID:Start the generator.
Aah! Aaaggghhh!
Gaaahhhh!
( Norm screams )
( Monster shrieks )
Hey, I'm sorry.
I mean, how the-- how the hell
was I supposed to know what you meant?
You said you heard something.
How was I supposed to know
what you meant?
You should've said
what you meant better.
I don't know, I thought maybe
it was a big bird or some--
You got that kid killed!
Did you get a good look at it? Huh?
Did you get a good look
at what you did?
- Huh?
- David!
Don't hit him anymore!
Doesn't solve anything!
You two assholes,
you got that kid killed!
And I got his fuckin' blood on me!
( Groaning )
( David panting )
Okay, I'm done.
Okay.
- What's next?
- Kill the generator.
That's the first thing.
JIM: I'm sorry.
DAVID: Jesus Christ! Oh, God!
JIM: I'm-- I'm sorry about the kid.
Oh, God. Oh, God. Oh, God.
We oughta get out of here.
( Coughing and retching )
Hey, we didn't twist his arm.
Yeah, he's a fuckin' kid.
He's supposed to be stupid.
What's your excuse, huh?
Get outta here.
Go back in the market.
Stay by the door.
Don't say anything, to anybody.
Not yet.
( Generator whirrs )
( Generator stops )
OLLIE: ( softly ) Shit.
David? Need a little light here.
We have to tell 'em.
The people in the market,
we have to stop 'em going outside.
They won't believe us.
They have to.
I'm not sure I believe it.
I was here.
W-What we saw was impossible.
You know that, don't you?
I mean, what--
What do we say?
How do we convince them?
Ollie, what the hell were
those tentacles even attached to?
Oh, my God!
Are-- are you all right?
DAVID: Shh! Yeah, yeah, yeah,
it's not my blood. I'm fine.
W-What the hell happened?
I'll explain. Give me a minute, okay?
I need to deal with something first.
Please, I've got to--
I can't let Billy see me like this.
He's scared enough.
Just give me a minute.
Keep him distracted. Okay?
Okay.
JIM: Hey, look,
I'm sorry about Norm.
Me too.
I mean, I ain't makin' excuses,
I'm just ea yin'.
Look, we need to tell people.
No need to say how it went down
or anything like that,
but, uh, we're in the deep shit here.
People need to know.
MYRON:
What about the out-of-towners?
We got plenty of them in the store.
Where do we even start?
- OLLIE: Brent Norton?
- JIM: That windbag?
He's an important attorney in New York.
That fellow could be
on the bench one day.
Counts a lot with people of this town,
or-- or anywhere.
- MYRON: Yeah, that's right.
- Do it quick, David.
We've got to discuss how we're gonna
stop that thing getting in here.
W-wait. What do you mean getting in?
You shut the loading door.
Yeah, but the entire front of the store
is plate glass.
Jesus Christ.
NORTON: I was wondering
where you'd gotten to.
DAVID: Um, listen...
that guy that came in here,
the one with the bloody nose...
( conversation continues indistinctly )
...they're-- they're--
We saw tentacles.
- Ain't goin' very well, is it?
- Unh-unh.
- You... what?
- Come here, you've got--
Come here.
Tell him.
It's true.
Tentacles. Yeah.
Um, gentlemen, um...
I'm sorry, I--
I'm just not that stupid.
I mean, what do you take me for?
I'm shocked.
I'm shocked. It's pretty tasteless using what's
happening here to try to make me look like an idiot.
No, no, that's not
what's going on here.
Look, come back
to the loading dock, okay?
I'll show you.
Blood. A chunk of tentacle
on-- on the floor.
No.
No? What do you mean no?
No. We've got real problems
to deal with here,
and this pathetic attempt at a joke
has gone far enough.
Mr. Norton, what reason
could we possibly have--?
Oh, please! Please!
This is payback for the lawsuit
that I filed against him last year,
and you guys are backing him up.
So winning wasn't enough, huh?
You wanted to humiliate me some more,
show me a rubber snake
while these-- these hicks
stand around laughing their asses off.
- Watch who you callin' a hick!
- Myron! Myron!
- Hey, hey, fuck--!
- JIM:Mr. Norton, I swear,
you have got us all wrong.
You're not too crazy about,
um, out-of-towners, are you?
I only spend my money,
and I pay my taxes here,
and I have seen you
talking behind my back.
Y'all stick together.
Well, don't I feel foolish?
I actually thought you were
being kind to me today,
and, well, thanks
for setting me straight.
And I'm glad that tree fell
on your boathouse, you know that?
Glad. Smashed it in
pretty good, didn't it? Fantastic.
Now, all of y'all,
just stay out of my way.
I know you're scared, man.
I'm scared too.
- Lives are at stake around here.
- David--
Okay, my son's life.
Now, I need you.
Brent, please, get your head out of your ass.
All right, I'll drag you back there
if I have to. Come here.
David, get-- get your goddamn hands off of me!
I'll sue your ass again!
Sue your ass, and this time
you'll go to jail!
This man assaulted me.
He assaulted me.
You were witness to it.
This man's crazy.
He's crazy.
No.
He isn't. I wish he was, but he isn't.
( Scoffs )
E-everyone in the store,
you want to come back here?
There's something you need to hear.
It concerns you all.
Okay.
BUD: W-w-wait. I don't know
what you people think you're doing.
You're drinking?
For Christ's sake, Ollie.
Do you want me to report you?
You want to lose your job?
Look, I'm gonna be taking down names,
starting with you.
And I am prepared to file
a police report.
- Fine, Bud, write down your names.
- I will.
But in the meantime,
shut the fuck up and listen.
This is Mr. David Drayton.
You need to hear what he's got to say
if you're thinking about leaving.
DAVID: ...go hang out
with the ladies, all right?
Listen, don't be scared.
It's okay.
Okay.
This is how it is.
Now, I don't know
what this mist is...
but there are things in it,
and they're dangerous, like Dan said.
That's right.
That's exactly right.
MAN: What kind of things?
I never saw it.
It happened too fast.
I got knocked down.
Five of us went back
in the loading dock.
It was Jim, Myron, Ollie...
me...
Norm, the bag boy.
- We opened the door...
- Where's Norm?
...so Norm could go out
and clear the vent for the generator.
Something come out of the mist
and took him.
- Took him?
- What do you mean?
Just... killed him.
I mean dragged him off.
Now, guys, I don't know
what these things are.
All we saw were tentacles.
( Onlookers muttering )
WOMAN: Tentacles?
NORTON: Tentacles, he says.
Tentacles from Planet X.
It's a lie, you know.
I mean, all these people do
is just lie each other up.
It's a pile of shit.
Of course it's a lie.
Of course it's a lie. It's lunacy.
From the look of it, the tentacles
are coming out of the beer cans.
All right, uh, Bud,
don't take our word for it. Go look.
DAVID: ( softly )
Over there.
What the hell is that?
( Sizzling sound )
It appears we may have a problem
of some magnitude here.
Yeah, just keep 'em in line. Thanks.
Let me...
help these people.
Let me--
let me preach Your word.
Let me shine Your light,
'cause they're not all bad.
They can't all be bad.
Some can be saved, can't they?
Yes.
Some can be brought...
to heaven's holy gates
through Your grace.
I have to believe that,
though I know most will swim
in the lake of fire forever.
If I can save a few...
even one...
then my life will have counted
for something.
I will have pulled my weight.
I will have earned my place at Your side.
I will have served a purpose
here on this earth.
Hello?
( Mrs. Carmody sniffles softly )
What?
I just need to use the bathroom.
Oh.
Okay. Well, then, have at it.
Ma'am...
I-- I just want you to know
that it's okay--
Being scared, I mean--
And, well, if you need a friend--
You know, someone to talk to.
I have a friend--
God up above.
I talk to Him every day.
Don't you condescend to me.
I'm sorry?
Not ever.
You don't mock me.
That's not what I was doing.
Well, I'll tell you what--
The day I need a friend like you,
I'll just have myself a little squat
and shit one out.
Maybe you do believe this.
Maybe they're not lies,
they're delusions. Whatever.
Uh, the fact remains,
the evidence here is flimsy.
- It's bordering on ludicrous.
- Hey, this isn't a courtroom.
You're not arguing a case, and you're doing
nothing but damage, talking the way you are.
And you can throw as much cow's blood
around the loading dock as you want to.
- You still haven't fooled anyone.
- OLLIE: Leave it alone, David.
You can't convince
some people there's a fire
even when their hair is burning.
Denial is a powerful thing.
Well, keep talking.
I'll have no part of it,
nor would any thinking person.
Keep thinking, Mr. Lawyer.
There's no defense
against the will of God.
There's no court of appeals in hell.
There's no defense here, either.
Not even with all the fertilizer in the world,
not even if you stack it as high as you can.
It's still just bags of shit, isn't it?
Those of you who want to discuss
this thing rationally
to find a means of rescue
are welcome to join me.
Those who want to stack dog food...
knock yourselves out.
We got those windows taped up
as best we could.
It should help.
Yeah, think so?
Duct tape and dog food bags.
That bad?
It's not good.
There's none so blind
as those who will not see.
Open your eyes.
Let the scales fall away.
This has all been written.
Revelations, chapter 15:
"And the temple was filled with smoke
"from the glory of God
"and from His power,
"and no one could enter the temple
until the seven plagues
of the seven angels were completed."
Well, what are you saying?
What are you proposing?
That we all prepare...
to meet our Maker.
JIM:Oh, prepare to meet shit!
Lady, your tongue
must be hung in the middle
so that it can waggle at both ends.
MRS. CARMODY:
The end time has come,
not in flames, but in mist.
JIM: Come here!
MYRON: Easy! Back off!
How about if your ass prepares
to meet my size-10 work boot.
- How about that?
- Hey, there's no call for that.
Myron, please,
calm your friend down.
MRS. CARMODY: I'm trying
to save your soul, you stupid man.
- Doubters will doubt till the end.
- It's okay.
No, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
A monstrosity did pull
that poor boy away.
Things in the mist--
do you doubt?
Do you?
Then go out.
Go out and say,
"How do you do."
Shut up, lady.
For God's sakes.
Look, you'll have to stop now.
You're scaring the children.
They should be scared.
Oh, yes, they should.
Their beautiful, pure little minds
have been corrupted with lies.
Lies.
All this talk of a modern God,
or no God.
There is one God.
The God of the Israelites.
And He is a stern and vengeful God,
and we have been mocking Him
far too long,
and now He demands
retribution in blood.
It is time to declare yourselves.
Take sides--
The saved and the damned.
Read the Good Book.
It calls for expiation.
- Blood!
- What?
Blood.
Little Normie was first,
and now God calls the rest of us.
The bill is due.
It must be paid.
As Abraham prepared
to sacrifice his only son
to prove his love for God, so--
- Enough.
- ( onlookers gasp )
- Ohh.
- Another down payment.
A few more pennies in the jar.
Now, that's nice, see.
I can't smack her, but it's okay for you.
I-I'm sorry everybody,
but this lady's perspective is
a little too Old Testament for my taste.
MRS. CARMODY:
They'll come for you.
Maybe tonight,
when darkness comes.
They'll come tonight,
and they'll take someone else.
See if they don't.
And when they do,
you will cry to God,
and you will beg Mother Carmody
to show you the way.
OLLIE: That's fine.
But until then,
if you don't shut up,
I'll wrap this tape around your mouth.
You just try it, Ollie Weeks.
And you, bitch...
you hit me again...
if you dare.
You'll be on your knees to me
before this is through.
Those of you who aren't local should know
that Mrs. Carmody is known in town for being...
unstable.
No shit.
What was your first clue?
SOLDIER: Shh.
- Hi.
- What's up, little dude?
How come your friends
don't come get us?
They got tanks and stuff, right?
Why can't you just call 'em?
Phones don't work.
But don't you got, like, a radio?
Hey, champ, what's going on?
I want their friends
to come rescue us.
They would if they could, pal.
They're stuck here just like us.
- But--
- Shh.
Now, guys, we could use
a hand over there.
SOLDIER: Yeah, sure thing.
SOLDIER #2:
Troop, off your asses.
- DAVID: You all right?
- I don't like that scary lady.
Oh, man, I don't either.
But you know what?
Maybe she's scared too.
You think?
You think Mommy's okay?
( Sighs ) Billy...
I'm sorry about the times
I was bad to her.
Aw, hey.
Mommy loves you very much.
And I'll bet she's fine.
And I promise you,
I'm gonna do everything I can
to get us back to her.
- Okay?
- 'Kay.
- Yeah?
So, we can use the charcoal fluid
and the mops to make torches.
And we've got knives and stuff, God knows.
This may be a silly question, Bud,
but... do you happen to have a gun in the store?
Here? No. Please.
This-- this isn't Los Angeles.
I've got a shotgun in my truck.
I could try for it if you want.
Oh, God, I don't think that'd be
a good idea, Mr. Cornell.
Hold on.
This gun, um...
my husband's idea.
He's away on business a lot.
It's not even loaded.
Ain't much use unloaded, ma'am.
AMANDA: Um...
DAVID:
You know how to use that?
Well, I shot it once on a pistol range.
Hit the target a few times.
So, we got a gun.
Anybody know how to shoot it?
Well, I mean?
I do.
You?
( Scoffs )
Ollie. Please.
Some target shooting.
State champion in '94.
- MAN:You're crazy if you go out there!
- NORTON: Let us pass! Let us pass, please!
Let's just talk this thing through.
NORTON: We have, and we've
made our decision. We're leaving.
Hey, Mr. Mackey's gonna barbecue
some chicken on the gas grill.
- Why don't we just sit down and just--
- What, and let you keep on talking?
No, I've been in far too many
courtrooms to fall for that.
You've already psyched out
half a dozen of my people already.
AMANDA: Your people?
What kind of talk is that?
They're people, that's all.
Now-- now listen, everyone.
We are experiencing
some kind of disaster.
I don't know whether
it's manmade or natural,
but I do know that
it's definitely not supernatural
or biblical,
and, no offense, Mrs. Carmody,
but the only way
we're gonna help ourselves
is to seek rescue.
We're going out.
- Brent, look.
- I'm not discussing this any further.
I know. I just want to ask a favor.
Tie this around your waist.
What for?
It'll let us know you got
at least 300 feet.
I'll do it.
- Are you throwing in with them?
- Me? No thanks.
I think your man there
is a little too tightly wound.
Gonna get somebody killed.
But I'm thinkin' we could use
that shotgun of yours.
I saw where you parked
when I pulled in.
Red pickup, right?
Far entrance?
Son, you got brass balls.
The shells are
in the glove compartment.
Drive it back.
All right.
Just see they're paying out this line.
Line's up, I'll cut her loose,
just so you understand.
DAVID: Yeah.
You sure there's no way
I can talk you out of this?
David... there's nothing out there.
Nothing in the mist.
What if you're wrong?
Then, I guess...
the joke would be on me after all.
We're gonna send back help.
You'll die out there.
All of you.
Hey, crazy lady,
I believe in God too.
I just don't think He's the bloodthirsty asshole
you make Him out to be.
Well, you take that up with the devil
when you run into him.
You just chat it over at your leisure.
Well, let's strike out
toward the center of town.
Keep it loose.
DAVID: Nice and easy.
OLLIE: ( low ) Keep going.
( Onlookers murmur )
JIM: Look.
It's going.
They're doing good.
Aah! Aaahhhh!
( Onlookers screaming )
( Cord whistles sharply )
MAN: Put it down!
Ohh! Pull!
MAN: Oh, my God!
I'm slippin'!
Pull! Back up! Back up!
Back up!
( Onlookers scream and shout )
Get it off!
Oh, my God.
( Woman sobbing )
- JIM: Aw, sh--
- MRS. CARMODY: Blood!
Awww, sh--!
MRS. CARMODY:
Oh, my God!
- ( Onlookers shouting )
- Oh, my God!
( Onlookers screaming )
Cut the rope!
Shut the door!
Now do you see?
Now do you believe?
OLLIE:
About a half-hour of daylight left.
Guys, how's it going
with these work lights?
- We're gettin' 'em rigged up all right.
- Yeah, check it out.
All right, all right.
Save it, save it.
These batteries ain't topped up.
You turn the lights on,
it's gonna drain 'em quick.
How quick?
- Five minutes, maybe ten.
- Yeah, if that.
Okay, emergencies only.
If something gets in the store.
( Sighs ) Holy Jesus,
you scared the shit outta me.
Oh, Sally, I'm sorry, really.
I thought I'd come in and say hi
and see how you were holding up.
- Hi.
Barely. How about you?
I'm worried about my folks, I guess.
You know, they live
up on Shorm Road.
That's less than
five miles from here.
How 'bout yours?
Well, they're out of town right now.
They're at my aunt's in Boston, so...
That's lucky.
That means they're okay.
I hope so.
So... how soon you shipping out?
Uh, couple weeks.
Scared about going over there?
( Softly ) Yeah.
- Hey, Wayne?
- Hmm?
How come you never asked me out?
We flirted all through high school.
I know you like me.
( Chuckles )
So how come?
I'm stupid, I guess.
Oh, shit! I'm sorry.
Don't be. I just-- I just didn't really want it
to happen like this, you know?
Some shitty locker room at work.
Can we just stay in here a while, then?
I mean, just-- just you and me.
- DAN:The parking lot lamps turned on.
- OLLIE:They're on a timer.
Must be a different municipal line.
DAN: Maybe we could
tie into them somehow,
get some electricity in here.
That'd mean walking out the door.
- Gaaaahhhh! God!
- ( woman screams )
Oh, my God!
- OLLIE: David! David!
- ( Indistinct )
WOMAN: ...you sure?
Look!
My God.
Are those bugs?
Not like any I've ever seen.
MRS. CARMODY:
"They came out of the smoke,
"locusts upon the earth,
"and unto them was given power
even as the scorpions
of the earth have power."
( Gasps ) Wow.
Look at those stingers.
Dear God.
Subtitle | www.movieddl.me
Holy shit!
( Monster shrieks; onlookers scream )
( Screaming )
Myron, get the ones in the back!
God, I think they're attracted to the light.
- ( Screaming )
- OLLIE: Look out, look out, look out!
The light! Douse the light!
Look out! Look out!
( Screams and weeping )
Move! Move!
DAVID: Light, light,
light, light, light!
( Glass crashes )
"And there came a voice
from the temple
"saying to the seven angels,
" 'Go your ways
and pour out the vials
of the wrath of God upon the earth.' "
( monsters shrieking )
DAVID: Ollie, the glass is gonna give!
- DAVID: Shit!
- OLLIE: Oh, my God, they turned on all the lights!
- OLLIE: Jim! Myron!
- DAVID: Fire!
- OLLIE: Douse the lights!
- DAVID:Fire! Lighter!
- Come on, come on!
- ( lighter flicks )
Aah!
Whoa!
Oh, ugh!
Sally, look out!
No!
Ohh! Oohhhh!
( Groaning )
Let me see, let me see.
Let me see, sweetheart, let me see.
No, you're gonna be okay.
You're gonna be okay.
Let me see. Let me see.
You're fine. You're gonna be okay.
You're gonna be okay.
Give me the lighter!
Put it on fire!
Come on!
Come on, come on!
Breathe, breathe, breathe, Sally!
Goddamn childproofing sons of bitches!
Aaahhhh!
AMANDA: Oh, shoot it! Shoot it!
Shoot it! Shoot it!
I can't! I'll smash the window!
AMANDA: ( screaming ) God!
Oh, God! Ohh!
- Aaahhh!
- Go! Go!
( Screams and shouts )
OLLIE: Get down!
( Screaming and shouting )
OLLIE: Shit!
- Ollie, you want these lights on or off?
- Leave 'em on.
( Screaming and shouting )
Aah! Aaahhhh!
Oh, God!
Ohh! Ohhh! Kill it!
Aaaaahhhhhh!
( Crunching )
( Gasping )
MAN:Bring torches!
Bring something to keep 'em out!
Come on.
( Sally groaning )
WAYNE: Sally!
( Screaming and shouting )
Where are the goddamn extinguishers?
WOMAN: What's happening?!
( Monster shrieking )
Get it! Get it! Get it!
MAN:Bring torches.
We need torches at the window!
Plug that hole!
Dad!
Down! Down! Lay down!
( Mrs. Carmody gasping )
Ohh.
My life...
my life for You,
Your will be done.
( Nervous titter )
- ( Screams and shouts )
- Daddy!
Bugs! Daddy!
( Gunshot )
( Onlookers scream )
( Monster shrieks )
- Nooooo! Billy!
- Daddy!
- Billy!
( Monster shrieking )
HATTIE: Billy! Oh!
Dad!
HATTIE: Billy, come back here.
- Dad!
- Billy, please!
( Monster shrieks )
HATTIE: Billy!
( Gunshot )
( Onlookers scream and shout )
( David panting )
MAN: Come on, let's move it!
MAN #2: Somebody please
come over here and help.
- ( Injured man screaming )
- MAN #3: Here's some tape!
MAN #4:I'm right here.
I'm right here. Don't worry.
MAN #5: Hurry up with the blankets!
INJURED MAN:
It hurts so bad! Please!
It hurts so bad!
MAN: Block it up here.
Get me some more bags!
DAVID: Did we get 'em?
Did we get 'em all?
WOMAN: She was right.
She said that it would happen like this.
She said that
they would come at night.
She told us someone would die.
( Monster snarling )
( Monster grunting and chewing )
( Grunts ) Mommy.
Ohh, shh, shh, shh.
It's okay.
It's okay, it was just a dream.
It's just a bad dream.
BILLY: I want my mommy.
I know.
I know. Of course you do.
- Shh.
- BILLY: I wanna go home.
Just sleep.
Everything'll be better in the morning.
Think he likes you.
( low ) Well, I hate that
I had to lie to him.
You have kids?
No.
I always wanted to, but...
things haven't been working out.
Right now I'm thinking
maybe that's for the best.
I saw creatures
fly into the store tonight that--
They shouldn't exist.
I keep thinking I'm gonna
wake up in a rubber room.
You're not alone in that.
We're all right there with you.
This isn't gonna end, is it?
OLLIE: David.
It's Joe. He's getting worse.
( Sighs ) Joe.
How you holdin' up, partner?
JOE: ( labored )
David... is that you?
Yeah, pal, how you doin'?
( low ) It's bad. He's bad.
Didn't know anything
could hurt like this.
If you guys can't help me...
you-- you gotta end it, okay?
Ollie's got that gun, right?
- JOE: Right?
- No. No way.
JOE: You can't fuck with me on this, bro.
Not with me like this.
I'll do it.
( Crying ) Just give me the gun.
DAVID: Hey, hey. Shh.
- We're not there yet, okay?
- Oh, please!
Joe, now, listen.
Pal... we're gonna work something out.
I just need you to hang in
a little longer, okay? Can we do that?
( Joe weeps softly )
DAVID: Stay with him.
I'll be back.
Hattie, I need to go to the bathroom.
Will you watch Billy?
Hattie.
See anything?
DAN: The last of those bugs
went away about four.
Dawn's coming.
What's on your mind?
DAVID: It's Joe.
We don't get him on some serious antibiotics,
he's gonna die of infection.
OLLIE: Plus he needs
painkillers in the worst way.
All-- all-- all we got here
is liquor and aspirin.
You-- you thinkin' about goin'
to that pharmacy next door?
Irene Reppler says
they've got Silvadene--
You know, the stuff
they use in burn wards.
- She knows where they keep it.
- Slow down.
You can't actually be thinkin' of doin' this.
I'm also thinkin' beyond that.
We have to get out of here.
- I mean permanently.
- Why? We got plenty to eat!
And what happens when one of those things
decides to break through this window?
I'm talkin' one of the big ones,
like the one that killed Norm.
Yeah, and that flaming torch idea
didn't work so well, did it?
We almost burned
the goddamn store down.
( Soft footsteps approaching )
It's Hattie.
( Moving quietly )
DAVID: Here?
DAN: All right,
gently, now. Gently.
BUD: One... two... three.
AMANDA: I don't know
how long she was there like that,
lying there next to us.
I thought she was sleeping.
I got my four-wheel drive.
It's out there.
Y-you're talking about leaving?
Well, we...
should hit the pharmacy first.
We gotta bring back
supplies for the injured.
I mean, if we don't,
Joe Eagleton's gonna die,
and we can't let that happen.
But after that...
look, my Land Cruiser
can hold eight people.
I say we drive south
as far as the fuel takes us
and try to get clear of this mist.
DAN: That's it?
That's the plan?
- That's what I got.
- No, you can't mean it.
Not after what happened
to Norton and his group.
No, no, no. Amanda, think.
Norton got over 200 feet
from this store.
That's how much rope played out.
I'm parked half that distance from here.
But who knows how far
this mist has spread?
It could be the entire eastern seaboard.
Yeah, it could be the whole world,
for all we know.
Wouldn't make us any less dead,
now, would it?
DAN: We have one gun.
- How many rounds?
- OLLIE: We got ten left.
Ten rounds. Jesus.
Okay, so ten.
Want another reason
to get the hell out of here?
I'll give you the best one. Her.
Mrs. Carmody.
She's our very own Jim Jones.
I'd like to leave before people
start drinking the Kool-Aid.
He's right.
Flakier people get,
the better she's gonna look.
No, I don't buy that.
It's obvious she's nuts.
Look, a few people maybe, but--
No, I count four.
She's preachin' to 'em right now.
By noon, she'll have four more.
By tomorrow night,
when those things come back,
she'll have a congregation,
and then we can start worryin'
about who she's gonna sacrifice
to make it all better.
Hmm?
You, Amanda?
My little boy?
DAN: He's right.
You don't have much faith
in humanity, do you?
None whatsoever.
I can't accept that.
People are basically good, decent.
My God, David, we're a civilized society.
Sure, as long as the machines
are workin' and you can dial 9-1-1,
but you take those things away,
you throw people in the dark,
you scare the shit out of them,
no more rules,
you'll see how primitive they get.
You scare people badly enough,
you can get 'em to do anything.
They'll turn to whoever
promises a solution,
or whatever.
Ollie, please, back me up here.
OLLIE: I wish I could.
As a species,
we're fundamentally insane.
Put more than two of us in a room, we pick sides
and start dreaming up reasons to kill one another.
Why do you think we invented
politics and religion?
Oh, Jesus, that's just... wrong.
DAVID: Look, nobody has
to decide anything now, okay?
First things first-- the pharmacy.
That'll be our test run.
Okay?
( Sighs heavily )
It's all right, Big Bill.
I'm gonna bring you back
some comic books.
I don't want them.
I want you to stay here.
I won't be gone long.
Just-- just next door.
Hey, you'll be safe.
Daddy--
Daddy, there are things out there.
Things--
Yeah. There's a lot
less of 'em in the daytime.
They'll wait. They'll wait in the mist
where you can't see 'em,
and then when you go
and can't get back in...
they'll come and eat you up!
- Shh.
- Daddy, don't go!
( Sobbing )
I'll be back.
Big Bill... I promise.
I'll be back, and then
I'm gonna take you home.
All right?
Together, we're going home.
If something happens,
anything at all, you cut and run.
You get your ass back in here,
for your boy's sake.
If something happens to me,
I want you to take care of Billy...
best as you can,
as long as you can.
Land Cruiser's yours now.
You-- you get him out of here.
You just keep drivin'.
Where do you think you're going,
Mr. David Drayton?
Are you so anxious
to make your boy an orphan?
My boy is no concern of yours.
Listen up.
We're going to the pharmacy.
We're gonna bring back some supplies.
Also, there may be people
trapped over there who need help.
- ( Onlookers murmuring )
- OLLIE: Listen, folks, listen!
We're not gonna take any chances.
If there's any trouble,
we'll come straight back here
to the supermarket.
And bring the fiends of hell
down on our heads, thank you.
WOMAN: She's right.
You'll make 'em notice us.
You'll make 'em come.
Why can't you just leave
well enough alone?
Lady, this what you call
"well enough"?
You wanna stop us?
You better explain to Bobby here
why we're not bringin' painkillers
and medicine back for his brother.
I'm goin', even if I have to go alone.
You'll die out there, young man.
You'll walk out that door
and be torn to shreds,
and then your hell-bound pride
will have them come get the rest of us.
Yes, they'll come back for all of us,
just like this good lady said.
Do you want that
to happen, people?
- ONLOOKERS: No!
- MRS. CARMODY: No! No! No!
Well, it is this kind of hubris
that brought the wrath of God
in the first place.
This kind of pride and defiance of--
( Onlookers gasp )
Shut up, you miserable buzzard!
You old bitch!
DAVID: No, no, no, no!
Stoning people who piss you off
is perfectly okay.
They do it in the Bible, don't they?
And I got lots of peas.
David, please, if you want to go,
now's the time.
How 'bout it, Army?
Any help from the armed forces?
I'll go.
IRENE: Jim Grondin.
I had you in school, didn't I?
Yes'm, me and my sister Pauline.
Pair of underachievers.
After you, Jim.
Yes, ma'am.
Oh, shit.
DAVID: That it?
That's everybody?
Everybody that's goin'.
- MAN: Yep.
- Okay.
DAVID: Single file,
one by one, all right?
Let's get this thing over with.
Let's go.
- JIM: After you.
- IRENE: Yes.
Stay together.
( Onlookers murmuring )
- MAN: Get the door.
- MRS. CARMODY: You know what?
- Mrs. Carmody, you're not helping.
- I don't care.
- Shut the hell up!
- You shut up!
DAVID: Save the batteries.
DAVID: ( low ) Shit.
They left the doors propped open.
OLLIE: ( low )
Think something got in?
DAVID: Let's just... get what we need,
get the hell outta here.
OLLIE: Yeah. Let's do that.
IRENE: ( low ) The meds are
over at the end there, in the cubicle.
( loud, sharp crash )
- DAVID: Will you not do that?
- JIM: ( low )I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
DAVID: ( exasperated )Oh, God.
Where's that Silvadene?
It's over behind David.
In the fridge. Check there.
Silvadene. Got it.
- Good.
- Ollie, what are we lookin' for?
- OLLIE: Penicillin.
- DAVID: Yeah.
OLLIE: ( normal volume )
Any strong antibiotics.
Yeah.
Pain meds like Vicodin or OxyContin.
- DAVID: Shh!
- OxyContin!
Hydrochloride?
DAVID: Penicillin.
( Soft scurrying sound )
Guys.
Hurry it up.
I hear something.
What?
( Soft scurrying sound )
DAN: Somethin' fuckin' weird.
Oh, God.
Oh, God!
No. Oh, no.
Oh, nooooo.
Oh, fuck.
IRENE: Look.
There's another one.
- OLLIE: Oh, my God.
- JIM: No, no, no.
Oh, no, no.
Guys, let's get out of here now.
- Aaaahhhhhh!
- OLLIE: Holy shit!
( Jim screaming )
JIM: Shit! Shit! Oh, shit!
M.P.:I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
Help me!
IRENE: Good Lord!
Help him!
( M.P. groaning )
DAVID: Son of a bitch!
This stuff ain't comin' off!
Oh, man!
He's glued to this fuckin' post!
( Hoarsely )
It's our fault.
It's all our fault.
DAVID: It's really stuck.
( Groaning )
M.P.: God, I can feel 'em!
I can feel 'em!
( Groaning )
WAYNE: Oh, my God!
Jesus!
Oh, my God.
Ohh! I--
Aaahhhh!
( Gasps )
Aah! Aaaaahhhhhh!
( Monster shrieks )
- ( Gunshot )
- There's more!
Ohh!
( Web sizzles )
( M.P. groans )
- Aah! Aah!
- DAN:There's another one! Hit it!
- Aah!
- OLLIE: What the hell is that stuff?
Ollie! One over there!
Ollie, there!
Got it!
There, there, there!
Shoot! Shoot!
- ( Monster squeals )
- Shit!
DAN:Where are they?
You see 'em?
- Where the hell are they?
- Aah! Aaaahhhhh!
Bobby!
( Monster shrieking )
( Bobby screaming )
- Aaahhhh!
- Hold on, man! Hold on!
- Hold on, man!
- Cut the strand!
- ( Gunshot )
- Help me!
( Gunshot )
IRENE: Let's get out of here!
( Screaming and shouting )
- A belt! Who's got a belt?
- I got a belt!
- Aaaaahhhhhh!
- Hold it tight.
- I got him, I got him. Hold on.
- I can't feel my--
DAVID: Pull it tight!
OLLIE: Look! Look!
Aaahhh! Aaaaahhhhhh!
Ohhhhhh!
Gaaahhhh!
DAVID: Light!
Light!
- ( Monster shrieks )
- God!
JIM: We gotta get outta here!
Come on!
WAYNE: Let's go, let's go,
let's go, let's go, let's go!
DAVID: Watch it, watch it, watch it!
( Monster shrieks )
DAN: Let's get out of here!
All right, go, go, go, go, go, go!
Come on!
DAVID: Come on!
( loud crash )
WAYNE: Oh, my God! We can't go.
Ollie! Ollie!
( Dry fires )
WAYNE: Kill it! Kill it!
( Grunting )
- Fuckers!
- Oh, no! Oh, God, he's dead!
He's dead! Get out of here!
Let's go, let's go!
Drayton, come on,
come on, come on!
Come on, Drayton, he's dead!
Come on!
( Onlookers scream )
JIM: Open the door!
( Shouting and screaming )
MAN: Where's Bobby?
Daddy!
MAN: Close up the doors!
Hurry up!
What happened?
JIM: They're dead!
They're all dead!
( Jim crying hysterically )
( Crying hysterically )
( Billy crying softly )
MRS. CARMODY:
...expiation, because we have seen
the earth scourged
with whips and scorpions.
We have seen the earth
vomit forth from her lips
obscenities and profanities
of such nightmare proportions.
And for these evil, lurking spirits,
and for these evil people...
How long was I out?
Most of the day.
You just came over here,
lay down, and went to sleep.
Just passed out, is more like it.
MRS. CARMODY:
What will stop this Great Whore?
Just shut down for a while. Sorry.
MRS. CARMODY: How will it end?
CROWD: Expiation!
MRS. CARMODY: Expiation!
Do you remember yesterday when...
DAVID: How's Joe?
Dead. Joe died of his burns
while you were asleep.
We were just too late.
- MRS. CARMODY:I told you this would come!
- DAVID:Oh, God, I thought I was dreaming her voice.
AMANDA: No dream.
She's getting people whipped up.
That poor girl is dead,
and that boy is burnt in the back room!
She's got 'em believing she's a psychic;
she has a direct line with God.
Why wouldn't they?
Woman never shuts up.
Like those speeches
Castro used to make.
( Carmody's followers applauds )
Ollie says you're thinking of leaving.
I'm in.
DAVID: No. Sorry.
I mean, come on, you saw what
happened to Bobby... Mike...
I won't... do that again.
I won't be responsible.
You might want to reconsider that.
MRS. CARMODY: What will-- what will keep
these evil, these abominations at bay?
What will keep them away?
"The rock will not hide them.
The dead tree gives no shelter."
What will end it?
Let me hear it.
- Expiation!
- So what are we talking about?
- Yeah, say it again like you mean it!
Expiation!
Welcome to Sesame Street.
Today's word is "expiation."
Hallelujah! Hallelujah!
That boy hasn't been right
since the pharmacy.
His mind's just snapped. Gone.
Hasn't even been two days.
Not even two days.
CORNELL: I'm not spendin' the rest
of my life here, I'll tell you what.
OLLIE: I can quietly gather up
some bags of groceries
and hide them up at one of
the check stands by the door.
DAN: It was your idea.
It's your vehicle.
It'll be your call.
I'd rather die out there trying
than in here waiting.
( Followers applaud )
MRS. CARMODY:
Who will save them? No one.
These rocks will not hide them.
I want some idea of what we're up against.
I want to know what this mist is.
- I want to talk to the soldiers.
- Soldiers? What's that gonna do?
You heard what that M.P. said
at the pharmacy.
David, I'm not even sure
I knew he was talking.
The situation was insane.
He said he was sorry.
Wasn't that the word
he used-- "sorry"?
That's right.
He said it was their fault, right?
- AMANDA: What did he mean by that?
- That's what we're gonna find out.
Irene, stay with Billy, please.
MRS. CARMODY:
Verse 17!
"...poured out his vial into the air,
"and there came a great voice
"out of the temple of heaven
from the throne, saying,
" 'It is done! It is done!'
"And there were voices
and lightning,
and thunders,
and a great earthquake."
Yes! Come to me!
WAYNE: What?
- Where's your friends?
- I ain't seen 'em.
Not that big a store.
It's kinda hard to lose.
I ain't seen 'em, I said.
I look like their keeper?
- What do you want from me?
- What do you know about this mist?
I don't know nothin'.
I got nothin' to do with it.
That's not what the M.P. said in the pharmacy
before the spiders came out of his skin.
They're not in the store.
The only place we haven't looked
is the loading dock.
...because you know.
You saw the good face
of God tonight.
Yes? Tell us.
Here is an old man who has seen!
- Yes, he has seen!
- ( applauding )
MAN: Amen.
MRS. CARMODY:And I want to say,
do I want to walk with you
into my Father's hands?
Morales.
Donaldson.
Guys...
- It's the only place they can be.
- WAYNE: What?
OLLIE: Couldn't just disappear.
WAYNE: Look, I told you,
okay, I don't know where they are--
( Sharp gasp )
I didn't think they'd do it.
They said they would do it, and I just--
I told them what the M.P. said at the pharmacy,
and they swore they'd do it.
I just-- I didn't think they would. Oh, Jesus!
It's the Arrowhead Project, isn't it?
This mist, it's some kind of,
what, military fuck up?
What were you guys
messin' with up there, huh?
We got you now,
you sorry son of a bitch!
Get in there!
It was them!
It was them what done it to us!
It was them what brung down
the final wrath upon us!
Those two peckerwoods
that he's been with this whole time,
they hung themselves in the back
because they knew!
They knew it all along!
- He's crazy. He doesn't know--
- Get on your knees!
- ( Shouting )
- MAN: Stay out of it, Drayton!
They heard it too, didn't you?
All of ya!
All about the Arrowhead Project
and all that secret shit up on the mountain.
That's what brung it down on us.
That's what brung down the wrath of God!
MRS. CARMODY: Oh!
Private Jessup.
It wasn't me.
I'm just--
I'm stationed up there.
I'm not responsible--
- Bullshit!
- Hell, I'm a local!
Most of you people know me.
You stop your chicken shit whining
or I will cut your puling tongue out.
Now you tell us!
( Coughs )
MRS. CARMODY: Tell us.
Look, look. Okay, okay.
I heard stuff.
Stuff?
Yes, we all heard stuff.
Like how they, um...
how they thought
that there were other dimensions,
you know, other--
other worlds all around us,
and how they wanted
to try and make, um,
a window--
You know, so they could look through
and see what's on the other side.
Well, maybe your window
turned out to be a door. Didn't it?
Not mine! Those scientists'!
- Oh, the scientists!
- Yes, the scientists!
They must have ripped
a hole open by accident.
This other world
came spilling through to ours.
That's what Donaldson was saying
to me right before he killed himself.
I didn't understand the half of it.
It ain't my fault!
Oh.
Ain't. His. Fault.
- ( Angry murmuring )
- No, no, no.
Ain't nothin' ever anybody's fault.
But he denies it.
He points the finger,
this Judas in our midst.
CROWD: Judas!
David!
You! You!
Don't you know by now?
Don't you know the truth?
We are being punished.
For what? For going
against the will of God!
For going against
His forbidden rules of old!
Walking on the moon!
Yes! Yes!
- Or-- or splitting His atoms!
- MAN: Amen!
Or-- or-- or stem cells and abortions!
And destroying the secrets of life
that only God above has any right to!
Amen! Amen!
MRS. CARMODY:
Yes, I know! It is true!
And now we are being punished.
The judgment is being
brought down upon us.
The fiends of hell,
you see they are let loose,
and star Wormwood blazes!
And it is his fault!
No! No! It is not my fault! No!
They did it! They spit
in the eye of the Almighty!
No!
- ( Angry shouting )
- MACKEY:Get over there!
DAVID: No!
MACKEY: Judas!
OLLIE: Jim!
Kill him! String him up!
Stand up, you coward!
Unkh!
( Scattered applause )
Jesus!
DAVID: No!
Aaaahhhh!
MACKEY: Expiation!
- No!
- MAN: Stab him!
- Aaahhhh!
- Expiation!
Feed him to the beast!
Expiation!
Let the abominations
smell his blood!
No, no! No!
Aaaaahhhhh!
- Jesus! Wait!
- No, David!
Aaahhhh!
( Crowd screaming and shouting )
( Groans )
Aaahhhh!
( Weeping )
( Groaning and gasping )
( Door locks )
Aah! Aaahhh!
Aaahhhh!
Aaahhh! Aah!
( Monster roars )
Please.
( Onlookers scream )
( Distant monster roars )
MRS. CARMODY:
The beast will leave us alone tonight.
Tomorrow...
tomorrow, we'll just
have to wait and see.
BILLY: ( softly ) Daddy.
Daddy.
( Softly ) Sorry I left you, pal.
I'll never leave you again.
Promise?
But you have to give me
your best promise, okay?
Your very best promise,
and can never break it.
Tell me.
Promise you won't let
the monsters get me.
Ever. No matter what.
I promise.
I love you, Daddy.
I love you, Billy.
More than anything.
( Softly ) It's dawn.
Hey, pal, you ready to go home?
Come on.
Okay, I got the groceries
hidden at check stand number two.
Five bags. We can grab 'em
and get out the door.
Okay.
My car's parked in the center lane
of the parking lot, far end.
Whoever gets there first,
open up both doors,
and we'll all pile in
as fast as we can, okay?
Let's go.
Stealing food now?
Going out now, Mrs. Carmody.
Please stand aside.
You can't go out.
I won't allow it.
Won't allow it?
It's against God's will.
Don't you know that by now?
Haven't I proven myself
again and again and again?
Haven't I shown that I am His vessel?
What's the matter with you?
Don't you believe in God?
No one's interfered with you.
All we're asking for
is the same privilege.
You heard him.
It is these people
who brought this upon us.
They-- people who refused
to bend to the will of God,
and claim it privilege.
Sinners in pride.
Yes, haughty.
Privileged!
They mock us. They mock our--
our God, our faith,
our values, our very lifestyle.
They mock our humility
and our piousness.
They piss on us and laugh.
It's from them the blood
of human sacrifice must come.
From them...
- Come on.
- ...the blood of expiation.
JIM: Come on.
You try it.
Fuckin' try it!
Come on!
- MAN: Get 'em!
- We want the boy.
- We want the boy!
- You get back!
- Yeah!
The boy!
David! David!
Grab that boy! Grab him!
- Get off me!
- ( followers shouting )
Get off me! Get off me!
Grab him!
And get the whore too!
Grab her!
Kill 'em! Kill 'em all!
( Gunshot )
( Onlookers gasp and fall silent )
( Onlookers scream )
MAN: Stay down!
Stay down! Stay down!
( Debris clanks )
I-- I killed her.
Thank you, Ollie.
Let's go.
Get that ice machine
out of the way, please.
WOMAN: You killed her!
You murdered her!
I wouldn't have shot her, Dave,
not if there'd been any other way.
That's why I said thank you.
Okay.
Okay, then... let's go!
- ( Sharp thud )
- Get up, Myron!
- Come on! We gotta go!
- My ankle!
( Women sobbing softly )
Okay. All the way down!
Where are they?
Bud! Myron!
Ambrose!
I think I broke it!
Come on! Come on!
AMANDA: We gotta go!
Come on, come on!
IRENE: They're lost!
( Amanda gasping )
- Oh, Jesus.
- Ollie!
- ( monster roars )
Aaahhhh!
Aaaaahhhhhh!
- Oh!
- Aaahhh!
( Screaming and shouting )
( Ollie screaming )
AMANDA: Ohh!
Aaah! Aaaahhhh!
Aaah! Aaaaahhhhh!
IRENE: All that screaming!
DAN:Are they out there?
Can they see us?
( Honks car horn )
Let me-- let me in!
Let me in!
( Screaming )
( Screams die )
Are we going?
- No.
- Yeah.
- No! No!
- Yeah!
- Daddy.
- David.
- David, no.
- Daddy, no.
- David!
- Daddy!
Get back in the car!
- David!
( Screaming )
( Monster shrieking )
Oh, my God!
Aaahhh!
( Shrieking )
AMANDA: Oh, my God!
We gotta go.
( Engine starts )
( Distant monster roars )
DAVID: I told her I'd fix it.
Front window... broken open.
Tree.
My... grandfather's tree.
( Distant monster roars )
I'm sorry, David,
I'm just so sorry.
DAVID: Let's, uh... see how far this...
fuel takes us, huh?
( Engine humming )
Maybe we'll get clear of the mist.
( Giant, heavy footsteps )
( Massive bellow )
( Bellows )
( Engine faltering )
( Engine dies )
DAN: Well...
we gave it a good shot.
Nobody can say we didn't.
Nope.
Nobody can say that.
( Distant monsters roar )
( Sighs )
Well...
We got, uh...
four.
Four bullets.
But there's five of us.
I'll figure something out.
( Bullet drops into chamber )
( Distant monsters roar )
( Gunshots )
DAVID: Aaaaahhhhh!
Aaahhh!
( Weeping loudly )
( Dry firing )
Aah! Aah!
Come on!
( Softly ) Come on. Come on.
- Come on.
- ( distant bellow )
Come on.
Come on, come on!
Come on! Come on!
( Distant monsters roar )
( low rumble rising )
( Massive bellow )
( Helicopter passes overhead )
They're-- they're dead.
For what?
( Crying )
Aah!
Aaaaahhhhhh!
( Screaming )
( Helicopter rotors whirr)
( Ground vehicle passes)
( Distant helicopter approaches)
( Helicopter passes )